<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Mike Bridge - Dev Notes</title>
    <link>https://mikebridge.github.io/categories/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Mike Bridge - Dev Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>mike@bridgecanada.com (Mike Bridge)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mike@bridgecanada.com (Mike Bridge)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mikebridge.github.io/categories/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flask JSON Input Validation</title>
      <link>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/python-flask-kubernetes-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mike@bridgecanada.com (Mike Bridge)</author>
      <guid>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/python-flask-kubernetes-2/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve created a simple Python microservice using Flask in Part 1. Using that as a starting point, let&amp;rsquo;s take a quick side-trip through input validation before we deploy the whole thing on Kubernetes.
 Code for this can be found on GitHub. Or you can use this template as a starting point.
 Input validation We don&amp;rsquo;t have any validation yet, so let&amp;rsquo;s add that in. We want to have a 400 error of some sort, so let&amp;rsquo;s write a test for it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Python Microservices in Flask</title>
      <link>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/python-flask-kubernetes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mike@bridgecanada.com (Mike Bridge)</author>
      <guid>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/python-flask-kubernetes-1/</guid>
      <description>Code for this can be found on GitHub. Or you can use this template as a starting point.
 The Microservice Scenario So here&amp;rsquo;s the situation: you&amp;rsquo;ve added data scientists to your team, and they&amp;rsquo;re coming up with great ideas that they&amp;rsquo;re implementing in jupyter. Lots of these new bits and pieces need to make it into the rest of your non-python system, so you decide that these small bits of logic should be deployed separately as microservices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compress a Folder in PowerShell for use in Linux</title>
      <link>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/windows-tar-gzip-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mike@bridgecanada.com (Mike Bridge)</author>
      <guid>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/windows-tar-gzip-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://mikebridge.github.io/images/windows/fresh-tar.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Fresh Tar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasted quite a bit of time trying to find the correct way to zip a folder
in PowerShell so that it could later be extracted in a Linux docker
container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR;&lt;/strong&gt; Turns out the standard unix tar command is now standard-issue in
Windows—no need to use PowerShell functions at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging React Native/Android with IntelliJ on Windows</title>
      <link>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/intellij-react-native/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mike@bridgecanada.com (Mike Bridge)</author>
      <guid>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/intellij-react-native/</guid>
      <description>Facebook&amp;rsquo;s developers are mostly Apple People, so they don&amp;rsquo;t waste many mental cycles fretting over React-Native developers who are on other platforms. I don&amp;rsquo;t like straying too much from the main path when it comes to deciding on which tools to use, so I wondered if it was advisable—or even possible—to debug React Native at all on Windows. Google Search didn&amp;rsquo;t reveal much information about what Windows React-Native developers do when their app crashes with no error message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinect and Processing</title>
      <link>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/kinect-and-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>mike@bridgecanada.com (Mike Bridge)</author>
      <guid>https://mikebridge.github.io/post/kinect-and-processing/</guid>
      <description>I fell into a discussion with another soccer-dad last weekend as we watched our own children play indoor soccer about teaching kids to code. I talked about my experiences with Raspberry Pi, Scratch and Sonic Pi at the coding club we set up at my son&amp;rsquo;s school, and I mentioned that after reading Generative Art several years ago I pair-programmed some happy faces with my then-seven-year-old son in Processing:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>